<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Features on BB-Gr8</title>
    <link>https://olincollege.github.io/pie-2021-03/BB-GR8/features/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Features on BB-Gr8</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 11:52:18 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://olincollege.github.io/pie-2021-03/BB-GR8/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Electrical</title>
      <link>https://olincollege.github.io/pie-2021-03/BB-GR8/features/electrical/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olincollege.github.io/pie-2021-03/BB-GR8/features/electrical/</guid>
      <description>An Arduino controls all of the electrical components on BB-8. The Arduino is connected to various other components, including motors and a bluetooth module, to drive BB-8.
Circuit Design Here is the layout of our circuit:
The circuit includes an Arduino, a motor shield, and an HC-05 bluetooth chip. The bluetooth module pairs with a laptop and connects to the Arduino to send and receive commands. The motor shield sends power to the motors to drive them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical</title>
      <link>https://olincollege.github.io/pie-2021-03/BB-GR8/features/mechanical/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olincollege.github.io/pie-2021-03/BB-GR8/features/mechanical/</guid>
      <description>The main mechanical function of our BB-8 was to get a small robot to drive within a sphere. We built a bottom heavy robot inside of a spherical shell to mimic the functionality of BB-8.
Creating the Sphere Making the Ball Openable Fabricating a sphere that is smooth inside &amp;amp; out is hard enough, but building it such that we could easily access the robot inside made it even more challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://olincollege.github.io/pie-2021-03/BB-GR8/features/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olincollege.github.io/pie-2021-03/BB-GR8/features/software/</guid>
      <description>The software, written in Python, creates a clean interface for sending commands to BB-8, converting a joystick input to BB-8 commands.
Joystick The joystick is written in HTML/JS using a canvas element. Since this code is very generic and not central to BB-8&amp;rsquo;s functionality, the frontend of this was based off of an existing HTML joystick. This code was modified to send the position of the joystick (indicating magnitude and direction) to a Python server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firmware</title>
      <link>https://olincollege.github.io/pie-2021-03/BB-GR8/features/firmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olincollege.github.io/pie-2021-03/BB-GR8/features/firmware/</guid>
      <description>The Arduino&amp;rsquo;s firmware is all written in Arduino C and allows BB-8 to receive commands from a laptop and output speeds to its motors. The firmware is short and to the point, as firmware should be.
Code Summary The code starts by setting all of the speeds to zero. When a bluetooth signal is received, it parses the command, which gives it three numbers: the signed percentage power values for the three motors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Cost</title>
      <link>https://olincollege.github.io/pie-2021-03/BB-GR8/features/budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olincollege.github.io/pie-2021-03/BB-GR8/features/budget/</guid>
      <description>This project could be replicated with a $250 budget, as our team was resourceful in its use of materials to create an effective robot at a low cost.
Budget     Material Used Estimated Cost Amount Taken out of Budget     Borrowed Adafruit Motorshield $19.95 $0.00    Arduino Uno $23.00 $0.00    Roll of Duct Tape $8.58 $0.00    4V Rechargeable Batteries (3x) $7.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
